A Guide to the Papers of the Institute of Public Affairs, University of Virginia, 1927-1953
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Original Manuscripts-Round Table, Open Forum, Special Conference (Box 17-53)
  - Round Table: "The Function of the Church in Modern Life"
    - Summaries 1934 July 2 7 (Box 32)
  - Round Table: "Money: A Challenge to World Statesmanship"
    - "Twenty Years After," Robert S. Warren; "German Debt Conference of 1934: An Episode in International Economic Cooperation," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland; "Lessons from the Post War Experience," Dr. Ray Westerfield; "Money and Trade," Prof. F. Cyril James 1934 July 2 (Box 32)
    - "Analysis of the Present American Monetary Policy," Prof. James G. Smith; "Analysis of Present American Monetary Policy," Bernard Kilgore 1934 July 3 (Box 32)
    - "Money and Prosperity," Mr. Charles O. Hardy; "Money and Recovery," Ralph J. Watkins, Esq. 1934 July 4 (Box 32)
    - "Silver in the World Economy," Dr. E. A. Kincaid; "The Gold Standard in World Economy," Mr. Leo Pasvolsky 1934 July 5 (Box 32)
    - "National Monetary Systems and International Trade," Dr. Herbert F. Fraser; "National Monetary Systems and International Capital Movements," George W. Edwards, Ph.D.; "Monetary Systems and International Capital Movements Before and Since the War," Lewis I. Galantiére, Esq. 1934 July 6 (Box 32)
    - "An Approach to a World Monetary System," Louis Rasminsky; "Toward a World Monetary System," Mr. Willard E. Atkins 1934 July 7 (Box 32)
  - Round Table: "County, Government, and State Planning"
    - "The Counties and State Aid," Tipton R. Snavely; "Re-organization of County Government in New York State," Howard P. Jones 1934 July 2 (Box 32)
    - "Relationship of Local and State Planning," Charles J. Calrow 1934 July 3 (Box 32)
    - Address, Charles P. Taft, II; "Can Local Self Government Be Preserved in Rural Areas?" Paul W. Wager 1934 July 4 (Box 32)
    - "A Forecast of What Virginia Counties May Expect From the Optional Forms of County Government," Willard F. Day, Esq. 1934 July 5 (Box 32)
  - Round Table: "Management vs. Regulation in Government"
    - "Virginia Trial Justice Law," Hon. Lemuel F. Smith 1934 July 6 (Box 33)
    - "County Consolidation," John W. Manning 1934 July 7 (Box 33)
    - "The New Deal for Foreign Trade," Wallace Thompson 1934 July 9 (Box 33)
    - Address, Hon. Frank R. McNinch; "Governmental Management vs. Regulation in the Electric Power Industry," M.P. Tuttle, Esq. 1934 July 11 (Box 33)
    - "Management vs. Regulation by Government," Colonel M.C. Rorty; "The Relation of Government to the Railroad Industry," Joseph B. Eastman; "The Government and Industry," S.M. Du Brul, Esq. 1934 July 12 (Box 33)
    - "Government and Agriculture," Mordecai Ezekiel, Esq.; "Some Relations of Government to Investment Risk," Lawrence H. Seltzer, Esq. 1934 July 13 (Box 33)
    - "The Effects of Regulation on Industry," George Harrison Houston 1934 July 14 (Box 33)
    - Findings 1934 July 6-14 (Box 33)
  - Round Table: "The Interpretation and Evaluation of Recent Trends in Education"
    - "The Chicago Plan," George A. Works; "Reading for Honors at Swarthmore" and "Honors Courses in American Colleges," Dr. Robert C. Brooks 1934 July 9 (Box 33)
    - Address, Wilford M. Aiken, Esq. 1934 July 10 (Box 33)
    - Address, W. J. Polk, Esq.; "Who Shall Determine the Character of the Recreation and Education That Will Be Provided for Adults?," Joseph K. Hart 1934 July 11 (Box 33)
    - "Community Cooperation," Jacques Ozanne 1934 July 12 (Box 33)
    - "The Effect of the New Deal Legislation on Education," Floyd W. Reeves 1934 July 13 (Box 33)
    - "China's Educational Plans," Dr. Edgar W. Knight 1934 July 14 (Box 33)
  - Round Table: "Religious Education"
    - "What is the Effectiveness of Church School Teaching of Religion as at Present Conducted in Virginia," George C. Bellingrath 1934 July 9 (Box 33)
    - "How to Increase the Efficiency of the Sunday School," Dr. E. B. Paisley; "Leadership Training for Workers With Youth in the Church School," Dr. Z. B. Edworthy 1934 July 10 (Box 33)
    - "Improving the Vacation Summer School," Edna Baxter 1934 July 11 (Box 33)
    - "Building a Comprehensive Program of Weekday Religious Education," Dr. C. A. Hauser 1934 July 12 (Box 33)
    - "Discovering and Training Leaders," Miss Frances C. McLester 1934 July 13 (Box 33)
    - Description of Addresses, Dr. George Walter Fiske 1934 July 9-14 (Box 33)
  - Round Table: "Currents of Conflict in the Far East"
    - "Early Contacts and Attitudes," Grover Clark, Esq.; "Europe and the Far East--The Drive for Power and Profits in the Nineteenth Century," Dr. Harley Farnsworth MacNair 1934 July 9 (Box 33)
    - "The Drive for Converts," Dr. Nathaniel Gist Gee; "Development of Western Trade and Investment Interests in the Far East," Mr. Charles K. Moser; "Spreading Churches, Schools, and Hospitals," Dr. Nathaniel Gist Gee 1934 July 10 (Box 33)
    - "The Exchange of News Between the United States and the Orient," Miles W. Vaughn 1934 July 11 (Box 33)
    - "Some of the Problems that Confront the Chinese People," Zhi Meng (Chih Meng), Esq.; "Japan's Problems and Hopes," Prof. Masamichi Royama 1934 July 12 (Box 33)
    - "Recent Developments in Manchuria," Mr. Ben Dorfman; "New Forces in the Far East," Miles W. Vaughan, Esq. 1934 July 13 (Box 33)
    - "The Far East and the World Peace Machinery," Dr. Quincy Wright; "American Interests and Policy in the Far East," Grover Clark, Esq.; Summary 1934 July 14 (Box 33)
    - Discussion 1934 July 14, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Round Table: "An Evaluation of the Work of the National Industrial Recovery Act"
    - Address, Robert Wood Johnson; "The Future of N. R. A.," Russell E. Watson 1934 July 10 (Box 33)
    - "The Result of the N.R.A. Has Been Disadvantageous to the Workers," Dr. Carmen Haider 1934 July 11 (Box 33)
    - "The Consumer Under the N. R. A.," Dexter M. Keezer, Esq.; "The Consumer and the N. R. A.," Miss Isabel Leighton; "The New Deal and the Consumer," F. J. Schlink 1934 July 12 (Box 33)
    - "Trends in the Recovery Program," David Cushman Coyle 1934 July 13 (Box 33)
    - Findings 1934 July 9-14, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Round Table: "Protestant, Catholic, and Jewish Relationships in America"
    - "Historical Background for a Discussion of Protestant Catholic Jewish Relationships in America," Dr. Everett R. Clinchy; "The American Concept of Religious Freedom," Rabbi David de Sola Pool 1934 July 9 (Box 34)
    - "Sources and Psychology of Inter Group Prejudices as Illustrated by Relationships Between Christians and Jews," Prof. James V. Thompson; "Sources and Psychology of Prejudices Between Christians and Jews," Prof. Horace Kallen; "Specific Cooperative Steps Possible for Local Communities-Adult Education as Such a Step," Dr. Horace Kallen 1934 July 10 (Box 34)
    - "Sources and Psychology of Inter-Group Prejudices as Illustrated by the Relations of Protestants and Catholics," Rev. Claris Edwin Silcox 1934 July 11 (Box 34)
    - "Constructive Steps in the Relationships of American Protestants, Catholics and Jews," Dr. Abraham Cronbach; "Protestant-Catholic-Jewish Relationship in America," Rev. Thomas E. Mitchell, A.B., S.T.D. 1934 July 12 (Box 34)
    - "Notes for Talk on Citizenship," Walter J. Conaty; "Ethics," Dr. Abraham Cronbach; "Specific Cooperative Steps Possible for Local Communities," Prof. Claris Edwin Silcox 1934 July 13 (Box 34)
  - Special Conference: State Planning
    - "Federal Emergency Administration of Public Works," Charles W. Eliot II 1934 July 3 (Box 34)
    - "The Proper Organization of State Planning," Mr. Jacob L. Crane 1934 July 4 (Box 34)
  - Special Conference: League of Virginia Municipalities
    - "Relationships Between Municipalities and the Federal Government," Harold S. Buttenheim, Esq. 1934 July 6 (Box 34)
    - "Opportunities for Improved Housing in Virginia Cities," Lawrence V. Smith, Esq. 1934 July 7 (Box 34)
  - Radio Broadcasts
    - Dr. Thomas H. Reed 1935 (Box 34)
  - Evening Addresses
    - Vesper Service, "Religion for Today," Rev. John McDowell 1935 June 30 (Box 34)
    - Introduction, Dr. Charles G. Maphis 1935 July 1 (Box 34)
    - "Good Neighbor Policy in the Caribbean," Hon. Sumner Welles; "How to Share the Wealth," William B. Bell 1935 July 2 (Box 34)
    - "On World Reconstruction Since 1918," Dr. J. Anton de Haas; "Economic Factions in World Reconstruction," Peter Molyneaux 1935 July 3 (Box 34)
    - "The International Conference at Chatham House," Dr. C. O. Hardy; "The Evolution of Women Brain Trustees in the United States," Mrs. William Dick Sporborg; Address, Colonel Henry Breckinridge 1935 July 5 (Box 34)
    - "Child Welfare and Social Security," Katharine F. Lenroot 1935 July 6 (Box 34)
    - Vesper Service, "Finding God in a New World," Rev. William Adams Brown 1935 July 7 (Box 34)
    - "Like and Unlike in East and West," Ms. Pearl S. Buck 1935 July 8 (Box 34)
    - "Recovery by Statute," Dr. Neil Carothers 1935 July 9 (Box 34)
    - "The Blessings of Stability," Senator James W. Wadsworth; "The Constitution and the New Deal," General Hugh S. Johnson 1935 July 12 (Box 34)
    - "The Agrarian Side of the Mexican Revolution," Senor Dr. Licenciado Ramón Beteta; "The Constitution and the New Deal," General Hugh S. Johnson 1935 July 13 (Box 34)
    - "The Origins of the International Labor Organization," James T. Shotwell n.d. (Box 34)
  - Round Table: "Reconstruction: Problems in the Light of History"
    - Remarks, Dr. Ellis Paxon Oberholtzer; "The Fundamentals of Economic Recovery," Dr. A. J. Hettinger, Jr. 1935 July 1 (Box 34)
    - Address, Dr. Ernest Minor Patterson; "The Doctrine of Equality of Sovereign States," Clark M. Eichelberger, Esq. 1935 July 3 (Box 34)
    - "The Doctrine of Equality of Sovereign States," Dr. James C. Ballagh 1935 July 4 (Box 34)
    - "Labor, Unemployment, and Securities Against Unnecessary Risks," Colonel Henry Breckinridge; "Capitalism, Private Property, and Individual Liberty," Francis William Coker 1935 July 5 (Box 34)
    - "America... ," Dr. John Daniels 1935 July 6 (Box 34)
    - Summary 1935 July 1-6 (Box 34)
  - Round Table: "Economic Security"
    - "Social Trends and Security," Dr. William F. Ogburn 1935 July 1 (Box 34)
    - "The Place of the Government in the Solution of the Problem of Social Insecurity -the Social Security Bill," Dr. Raymond Pinchbeck 1935 July 2 (Box 34)
    - "Work Assurance," Jacob Baker, Esq.; "A State Welfare Official Looks at the Emergency Relief Program," Arthur W. James, Esq. 1935 July 3 (Box 34)
    - Summary, Dr. J. Douglas Brown; "The Dream of Old Age Security for Everyone," Morris Albert Linton, Esq. 1935 July 4 (Box 34)
    - "Health Insurance and the Medical Profession," Dr. J. C. Flippin 1935 July 5 (Box 34)
    - "A Comprehensive Program for Security Against Ill Health," Dr. Edgar Sydenstricker; "The Struggle for Health Insurance," Dr. Barbara Nachtrieb Armstrong; "Health Insurance and the Medical Profession," Dr. J. C. Flippin 1935 July 5 (Box 35)
    - "Modern Economic Trends and the Need for Social Security," Dr. Broadus Mitchell; "The Outlook for Economic Security," Dr. Joseph Pratt Harris 1935 July 6 (Box 35)
  - Round Table: "Latin-America: International, Economic, and Social Developments"
    - 1935 July 1 "Action on Equality for Women in the American Republics Since Montevideo," Ms. Helena Hill Weed (Box 35)
    - "The Latin American Policy of the United States, 1927 1935," Dr. Charles W. Hackett; "Some Basic Factors in the Cuban Situation," Dr. Leland H. Jenks 1935 July 2 (Box 35)
    - "Evening Address," Peter Molyneaux, Esq.; "Results, Actual and Anticipated, of Our New Reciprocal Trade Agreements with Latin America," Dr. Henry F. Grady 1935 July 3 (Box 35)
    - "The Agrarian Background of the Six Year Plan," Dr. William Wilson Cumberland; "Results, Actual and Anticipated, of the Mexican Agrarian Problem," Senor Dr. Licenciado Ramón Beteta 1935 July 4 (Box 35)
    - "The Social and Educational Program of the Mexican Government," Senor Dr. Licenciado Ramón Beteta; "The Catholic Attitude Towards the Social and Educational Program of the Mexican Government," The Reverend R. A. McGowan; "Social Phases of the Six Year Plan in Mexico [resume]," Dr. Joseph F. Thorning, S.J. 1935 July 5 (Box 35)
    - "Neutral Efforts to Settle the Chaco War," John C. deWilde, Esq.; "Rebuttal of Dr. Beteta to the Catholic Delegation Regarding the So-called Religious Controversy in Mexico," Senor Dr. Licenciado Ramón Beteta 1935 July 6 (Box 35)
  - Round Table: "European Relations: Rebuilding Peace"
    - "Italy Seeks Security Through Colonial Expansion," Dr. William E. Lingelback 1935 July 1 (Box 35)
    - "Economic Problems Confronting France," Monsieur Garreau Dombasle 1935 July 2 (Box 35)
    - "German Economic Policy 1919 1935," Dr. Karl Brandt; "The Depression in Germany and the Recovery Policy of the German Government," Dr. Gerhard Cohn; "Reciprocal Trade Agreements and the Revival of World Trade," Dr. Alvin H. Hansen 1935 July 3 (Box 35)
    - "The Foreign Exchange Problem in Relation to Trade Recovery," William S. Swingle, Esq.; "International Stabilization and Debts," Denys P. Myers, Esq. 1935 July 4 (Box 35)
    - "European Labor and Peace," David J. Saposs, Esq. 1935 July 5 (Box 35)
    - "Difficulties... of Normal Economic Relations in World Trade," Edward Jenkins, Esq. 1935 July 6 (Box 35)
    - Report 1935 (Box 35)
  - Round Table: "The Church in a Changing World"
    - "The Church and the Present Crisis," The Reverend John McDowell, D.D. 1935 July 1 (Box 35)
    - "Bible Sanctions and Resources for Social Change," The Reverend Cameron Parker Hall 1935 July 2 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and the Changing Role of Government," Rabbi Edward L. Israel 1935 July 3 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and a Reviving Caesarism," "A Mobilized Church, the Answer to a Divided World," The Reverend William Adams Brown 1935 Ju1 4 (Box 35)
    - "A Mobilized Church The Answer to a Divided World," The Reverend William Adams Brown 1935 July 5 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and Social Security in Industrial Life," The Reverend R. A. McGowan, Jasper E. Crane, Esq. 1935 July 6 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and Community Life," The Reverend Everett R. Clinchy, D.D. 1935 July 8 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and Social Security in Rural Life," The Reverend Henry W. McLaughlin, D.D. 1935 July 9 (Box 35)
    - "In Churches and International Security," The Reverend Albert D. Belden, D.D. 1935 July 10 (Box 35)
    - "The Church and Race Relations," The Reverend Don Frank Fenn, D.D.; Abstract of Talk, The Reverend John McDowell, D.D. 1935 July 11 (Box 35)
  - Round Table: "The Significance of American Membership in the International Labor Office"
    - "The Nineteenth Session of the International Labor Conference," Spencer Miller, Jr., Esq.; "Early Efforts at International Labor Standards," Dr. John B. Andrews 1935 July 8 (Box 35)
    - "The Significance to the Employer of American Membership in the International Labor Organization," Thomas G. Spates, Esq.; "Significance of American Membership... from the Stand-point of American Employers," Dr. Leland Rex Robinson 1935 July 9 (Box 35)
    - "International Labor Action," Leifur Magnusson, Esq. 1935 July 11 (Box 35)
    - "The Significance to Labor of American Membership in the International Labor Organization," John L. Lewis, Esq. 1935 July 12 (Box 35)
    - "The Importance of International Labor Standards," Dr. Samuel McCune Lindsay 1935 July 11 (Box 36)
    - "Cooperation of the United States with the International Labor Organization," Dr. Hugh S. Hanna; "The Cooperation of Voluntary Agencies with the International Labor Office," Dr. William Lonsdale Tayler 1935 July 12 (Box 36)
    - Findings 1935 July 13 (Box 36)
  - Round Table: "Taxation for Prosperity"
    - "Paying for Economic and Social Security," Dr. Joseph Pratt Harris; "Can We Achieve Prosperity by Taxation?," Noel Sargent, Esq. 1935 July 8 (Box 36)
    - Address, Arnold Frye, Esq.; "Tax Delinquency and Tax Collection," Honorable Henry F. Long 1935 July 9 (Box 36)
    - "Tax Relief for Real Estate," Harold S. Buttenheim, Esq., Peter Grimm, Esq., Dr. Herbert D. Simpson 1935 July 10 (Box 36)
    - "Drastic Tax Limitation and Its Effects as Indicated by a Quarter Century of Experience in Ohio," R. C. Atkinson, Esq.; "Tax Limitation," Dr. Jens P. Jensen 1935 July 11 (Box 36)
    - "The Sales Tax," Professor Carl Shoup; "The Mississippi Sales Tax: Its Administration and Results," Honorable A. H. Stone; "The Fallacy of the Sales Tax," Daniel Bloomfield, Esq.; "The Sales Tax," Harry McMullan, Esq. 1935 July 12 (Box 36)
    - "A Balanced Plan of Federal, State, and Local Taxation," Dr. James W. Martin; "A Balanced Program for Federal, State, and Local Taxation," Professor Joseph D. McGoldrich 1935 July 13 (Box 36)
    - Report 1935 July 8-13 (Box 36)
  - Round Table: "The Constitution and the New Deal"
    - "Two Amazing Years," Nicholas Roosevelt, Esq.; "The National Recovery Administration... ," Charles W. Putnam, Esq. 1935 July 8 (Box 36)
    - "Fabian Socialism in the New Deal," Demarest Lloyd, Esq. 1935 July 9 (Box 36)
    - "The People's Money," Dr. Walter E. Spahr; "Judicial Nullification," Honorable Fred J. Sisson 1935 July 10 (Box 36)
    - "The Principles of Constitutional Democracy and the New Deal," Raoul E. Desvernine, Esq.; "Nullification of Acts of Congress," Honorable David J. Lewis 1935 July 11 (Box 36)
    - "Which Road to Take?," J. Howard Pew, Esq.; "Business, the Constitution, and the New Deal," Mrs. Helen H. Miller; "Functions of the Federal Communications Commission," Albert E. Stephan, Esq. 1935 July 12 (Box 36)
    - "Speech," Captain William H. Stayton; "Today's Lesson for Tomorrow," Dr. James Hart 1935 July 13 (Box 36)
    - Summary 1935 July 8-13 (Box 36)
  - Round Table: "Contemporary Educational Issues"
    - Introduction, George B. Zehmer, Esq.; "On the Special Capacities of Adults for Continuous Education," Dr. H. M. Johnson; "Adult Interests as Related to Adult Education," Dr. Wayne Dennis 1935 July 9 (Box 36)
    - "Proposed Objectives of an Educational Activities Program for the Civilian Conservation Corps Camps of the Third Corps Area," Thomas G. Bennett, Esq.; "Public Agencies and Adult Education," J. L. B. Buck, Esq.; "Independent Agencies at Work," Miss E. Jeffries Heinrich; "Three Art Projects in the South and Their Significance," Miss Leila Mechlin; "Reviving Interest in the Handicraft Arts," Miss Clara R. Saunders 1935 July 10 (Box 36)
    - Address, Dr. Scott M. Buchanan; "Methods and Techniques in Adult Education in the Young Women's Christian Association," Miss Jane K. Dickey; "Methods and Techniques in Adult Education," Miss Mary B. Duncan 1935 July 11 (Box 36)
    - "Educational Issues in European Countries," Dr. Isaac L. Kandel 1935 July 12 (Box 36)
  - Round Table: "Conflict and Cooperation Across the Pacific"
    - "Geographical Setting," Commander Archer M. R. Allen; Address, Ms. Pearl S. Buck 1935 July 8 (Box 36)
    - "Unofficial Contacts in the Pacific Area," Frederick V. Field, Esq.; "Developing American Understanding of the Orient," Richard J. Walsh, Esq. 1935 July 9 (Box 37)
    - "Japan's Trade Expansion," Charles K. Moser, Esq.; "Japan's Government and Her International Relations," Dr. Harold Scott Quigley; "Legal Aspects of Japan's Case," Dr. Clifford Chesley Hubbard 1935 July 10 (Box 37)
    - "Foreign Concessions and Settlements in China," Dr. William C. Johnstone; "Cross Currents in China," Grover Clark, Esq. 1935 July 11 (Box 37)
    - "The Netherland East Indies," Dr. Adrian J. Barnaum; "Japan's Pacific Mandate," Dr. Paul H. Clyde 1935 July 12 (Box 37)
    - "The Philippine Islands," Colonel Donald C. McDonald; "Japan's Challenge," Dr. Keener C. Frazer 1935 July 13 (Box 37)
  - Round Table: "American German Relations"
    - "The German Element in the United States: Its History and Contributions to American Life," Dr. Walter A. Knittle; "A Survey and Estimate of Research in German American Cultural Relations," Professor Henry A. Prochmann; "America's Cultural Debt to Germany," Morris S. Lazaron 1935 July 8 (Box 37)
    - "German American Political and Economic Relations Since the War," Miss Mildred S. Wertheimer; "Cultural Relations Between 1919 1932," Dr. H. J. Simon 1935 July 9 (Box 37)
    - "American Opinion of the New Germany," Dr. Henry G. Hodges; "The Germany of Hitler Looks at the United States," Virginius Dabney, Esq. 1935 July 10 (Box 37)
    - "German Language and Literature in American Education," Dr. John A. Walz; Address, Dr. K. G. Frank 1935 July 11 (Box 37)
    - "American Contributions to German Life," Henry Albert Phillips, Esq.; "Americans in Germany," Ernst Schmidt, Esq. 1935 July 12 (Box 37)
    - "Present and Future Political and Diplomatic Relations Between the United States and Germany," Dr. Frederick K. Kruger 1935 July 13 (Box 37)
    - Summary 1935 July 8-13 (Box 37)
  - Round Table: "The Place of Religion in Character Education"
    - "The Jewish Position," Rabbi Edward N. Calisch, Ph.D.; "Relation of Church and State in Education The Protestant Approach," Dr. Stewart G. Cole 1935 July 8 (Box 37)
    - "The Relation of Church and State in Education," Dr. Paul Dawson Eddy; Address, Dr. Karl H. Stolz; "An Interpretation of the Modern Scientific Theory of Character Education," Dr. Stewart G. Cole 1935 July 9 (Box 37)
    - "The Function of Religion in Character Education," Dr. James V. Thompson 1935 July 11 (Box 37)
    - "Weekday Religious Education in Virginia," The Reverend Minor C. Miller; "The State National Commission in Ohio," Dr. Paul Dawson Eddy 1935 July 12 (Box 37)
    - "Character and Religion," Dr. Stewart G. Cole 1935 July 13 (Box 37)
    - Report and Summary 1935 July 8-14 (Box 37)
  - Open Forum
    - "Electrical Knowledge and Its Future Relationship to Mass Communication," General James G. Harbord 1936 July 13 (Box 37)
    - "Responsibilities of the Press in a Democracy," Franklyn Waltman 1936 July 16 (Box 37)
    - Question and Answer Discussion; Proceedings: Meeting of the Institute of Public Affairs 1936 July 17 (Box 37)
    - "Panel Discussion: Liberty of Expression in the Press, Radio, and Motion Pictures" 1936 July 16 (Box 38)
  - Round Table: "The Church and the Problem of Democracy"
    - "An Appraisal of Democracy," Frederick M. Davenport 1936 July 10 (Box 38)
    - "The Expanding Scope of Democracy: Is It Limited?," Professor Samuel McCune Lindsay 1936 July 11 (Box 38)
    - "Making Democracy Work: Is It Possible?," Professor Samuel McCune Lindsay; "The Problem of a Public Opinion in a Democracy," Dr. Herman S. Hettinger 1936 July 13 (Box 38)
    - "The Mutual Dependence of Education and Democracy," Dr. Charles J. Turck; "Democracy and Religious Education," Elizabeth Longwell 1936 July 14 (Box 38)
    - "Democracy and the Church: Are They Related?," Samuel McCrea Cavert; "The Country Church: A Factor in Democracy," Dr. Henry W. McLaughlin 1936 July 15 (Box 38)
    - Closing Address, Reverend John McDowell; Remarks Before the Round Table, Reverend R.A. McGowan 1936 July 16 (Box 38)
  - Round Table: "Public Opinion in a Democracy"
    - Address, Jerome D. Barnum; "The Magazine and Public Opinion," William L. Chenery 1936 July 13 (Box 38)
    - "Radio Broadcasting and Public Opinion," Philip G. Loucks; Paper, Raymond Gram Swing; "The Radio Station and Public Opinion," Lambdin Kay 1936 July 14 (Box 38)
    - "Motion Pictures and Public Opinion," F. W. Allport; "Motion Pictures and Public Opinion," Alexander Markey 1936 July 15 (Box 38)
    - "The Constructive Forming of Public Opinion," Edward L. Bernays; "Propaganda and Democracy," H. D. Lasswell; "Italian Propaganda Techniques," John Adams 1936 July 16 (Box 38)
    - Address, Felix Morley 1936 July 18 (Box 38)